CHAPTER 11. Who Stole the Tarts?
The King and Queen of Hearts were seated on their throne when they arrived, with a
great crowd assembled about them— —all sorts of little birds and beasts, as well
as the whole pack of cards: the naive was standing before them, in chains, with a
soldier on each side to guard him; and near the King was the White Rabbit,
with a trumpet in one hand, and a scroll of parchment in the other.
In the very middle of the court was a table, with a large dish of tarts upon it:
they looked so good, that it made Alice quite hungry to look at them—“ —“I wish
they’d get the trial done,” she thought, “and hand round the refreshments!”
But there seemed to be no chance of this, so she began looking at everything about
her, to pass away the time. Alice had never been in a court of justice before,
but she had read about them in books, and she was quite pleased to find that she
knew the name of nearly everything there.
“That’s the judge,” she said to herself, “because of his great wig.” The judge, by
the way, was the King; and he wore his crown over the wig
he did not look at all comfortable, and it was certainly not becoming. “And that
is the jury box thought Alice, “and those 12 creatures,” (she was obliged to say
“creatures,” you see, because some of them were animals, and some were birds,)
“I suppose they are the jurors.” She said this last word two or three
times over to herself, being rather proud of it: for she thought, and rightly too,
that very few little girls of her age knew the meaning of it at all.
However jerryman would have done just as well.
The twelve jurors were all writing very busily on slates.
“What are they doing?” Alice whispered to the Griffin They can’t have anything to put down yet,
before the trials begun.” “They’re putting down their names,” the Griffin whispered
in reply, “for fear they should forget them before the end of the trial.”
“Stupid things!” Alice began in a loud, indignant voice, but she stopped hastily,
for the White Rabbit cried out, “Silence in the court!” and the King put on his spectacles and
looked anxiously round, to make out who was talking.
Alice could see, as well as if she were looking over their shoulders, that all
the jurors were writing down “stupid things!” on their slates, and she could
even make out that one of them didn’t know how to spell “stupid,” and that he had
to ask his neighbor to tell him.
“A nice muddle their slates will be in before the trial is over!” thought Alice.
One of the jurors had a pencil that squeaked. This of course, Alice could not
stand, and she went round the court and got behind him, and very soon found an
opportunity of taking it away.
She did it so quickly that the poor little juror (it was Bill, the Lizard)
could not make out at all what had become of it; so, after hunting all about
for it, he was obliged to write with one finger for the rest of the day; and this
was of very little use it left no mark on the slate
Harold read the accusation!” said the King.
On this the White Rabbit blew three blasts on the trumpet, and then unrolled
the parchment scroll, and read as follows:— “The Queen of Hearts, she made some tarts,
All on a summer day: The Knave of Hearts, he stole those tarts, And took them quite away!”
“Consider your verdict,” the King said to the jury.
“Not yet, not yet!” the Rabbit hastily interrupted. “There’s a great deal to come
before that!” “Call the first witness,” said the King; and the White Rabbit blew three
blasts on the trumpet, and called out, “First witness!” The first witness was the
Hatter. He came in with a teacup in one hand and a piece of bread and butter in
the other. “I beg pardon, your Majesty,” he began, “for bringing these in: but I hadn’t
quite finished my tea when I was sent for.” “You ought to have finished,” said the King.
“When did you begin?” The Hatter looked at the March hair who had followed him into
the court arm in arm with the Dormouse 14th of March, I think it was,” he said
15th said the March here 16th added the Dormouse. “Write that down,”
the King said to the jury, and the jury eagerly wrote down all three dates on
their slates, and then added them up, and reduced the answer to shillings and pence.
“Take off your hat,” the King said to the Hatter.
“It isn’t mine,” said the Hatter. Stolen! the King exclaimed, turning to the jury, who
instantly made a memorandum of the fact.
“I keep them to sell,” the Hatter added as
an explanation; “I’ve none of my own. I’m a hatter.”
Here the Queen put on her spectacles, and began staring at the Hatter, who turned
pale and fidgeted.
“Give your evidence,” said the King; “and don’t be nervous, or I’ll have you
executed on the spot.” This did not seem to encourage the witness at all: he kept
shifting from one foot to the other, looking uneasily at the Queen, and in his
confusion he bit a large piece out of his teacup instead of the bread and butter
Just at this moment Alice felt a very curious sensation, which puzzled her a
good deal until she made out what it was: she was beginning to grow larger again,
and she thought at first she would get up and leave the court;
but on second thoughts she decided to remain where she was as long as there
was room for her. “I wish you wouldn’t squeeze so,” said the Dormouse, who was
sitting next to her. “I can hardly breathe.” “I can’t help it,” said Alice very meekly:
“I’m growing you have no right to grow here said the Dormouse. “Don’t talk nonsense,”
said Alice more boldly: “you know you’re growing too.”
“Yes, but I grow at a reasonable pace,” said the Dormouse: “not in that ridiculous fashion.”
And he got up very socally and crossed over to the other side of the court. All
this time the Queen had never left off staring at the Hatter, and, just as the
Dormouse crossed the court, she said to one of the officers of the court,
“Bring me the list of the singers in the last concert!” on which the wretched
Hatter trembled so, that he shook both his shoes off. “Give your evidence,” the
King repeated angrily, “or I’ll have you executed, whether you’re nervous or not.”
“I’m a poor man, your Majesty,” the Hatter began, in a trembling voice, “—and I hadn’t
begun my tea— —not about a week or so— —and what with the bread and butter
getting so thin— —and the twinkling of the tea—” “The twinkling of the what?
said the King.
“It began with the tea,” the Hatter replied.
“Of course twinkling begins with a T!” said the King sharply. “Do you take me for a
dunce? Go on!” “I’m a poor man,” the Hatter went on, “and
most things twinkled after that— —only the March Hare said—” “I didn’t!” the March hair
interrupted in a great hurry. “You did!” said the Hatter. “I deny it!” said the March
hair He denies it,” said the King: “leave out that part.”
“Well let any rate, the Dormouse said—” the Hatter went on, looking anxiously
round to see if he would deny it too: but the Dormouse denied nothing, being fast asleep.
“After that,” continued the Hatter, “I cut some more bread and butter But what did
the door mouse say?” one of the jury asked. “That I can’t
remember,” said the Hatter. “You must remember,” remarked the King, “or I’ll have
you executed.” The miserable Hatter dropped his teacup and bread and butter
and went down on one knee. “I’m a poor man,
your Majesty,” he began. “You’re a very poor speaker said the King.
Here one of the guinea pigs cheered, and was immediately suppressed by the
officers of the court. (As that is rather a hard word, I will just explain to you
how it was done. They had a large canvas bag, which tied up at the mouth with
strings: into this they slipped the guinea pig head first, and then sat upon
it.) “I’m glad I’ve seen that done,” thought Alice. “I’ve so often read in the
newspapers, at the end of trials, “There were some attempts at applause, which was
immediately suppressed by the officers of the court,” and I never understood what
it meant till now.” “If that’s all you know about it, you may stand down,”
continued the King.
“I can’t go no lower,” said the Hatter: “I’m on the floor, as it is.”
“Then you may sit down,” the King replied.
Here the other guinea pig cheered, and was suppressed.
“Come, that finishes the guinea pigs thought Alice. “Now we shall get on better.”
“I’d rather finish my tea,” said the Hatter, with an anxious look at the Queen, who
was reading the list of singers. “You may go,” said the King, and the Hatter hurriedly
left the court, without even waiting to put his shoes on.
“—and just take his head off outside,” the Queen added to one of the officers: but
the Hatter was out of sight before the officer could get to the door.
“Call the next witness!” said the King.
The next witness was the Duchess’s cook.
She carried the pepper box in her hand, and Alice guessed who it was, even before
she got into the court, by the way the people near the door began sneezing all at once.
“Give your evidence,” said the King shant said the cook. The King looked anxiously
at the White Rabbit, who said in a low voice, “Your Majesty must cross-examine
this witness.” “Well, if I must, I must,” the King said, with a melancholy air, and,
after folding his arms and frowning at the cook till his eyes were nearly out
of sight, he said in a deep voice, “What are tarts made of?” “Pepper, mostly,” said the cook
said a sleepy voice behind her.
“Collar that door Mouse the Queen shrieked out. “Behead that door Mouse Turn
that door mouse out of court! Suppress him! Pinch him! Off with his whiskers!”
For some minutes the whole court was in confusion, getting the door Mouse turned
out, and, by the time they had settled down again, the cook had disappeared.
“Never mind!” said the King, with an heir of great relief. “Call the next witness.” And
he added in an undertone to the Queen, “Really, my dear, you must cross-examine
the next witness. It makes my forehead ache!” Alice watched the White Rabbit as he
fumbled over the list, feeling very curious to see what the next witness would be like,
“—for they haven’t got much evidence yet she said to herself. Imagine her surprise,
when the White Rabbit read out, at the top of his shrill little voice, the name “Alice